# PRAKHHAR MAKHIJA

prakhharmakhija@gmail.com

**613-795-1884** 

in LinkedIn

Portfolio Website

### **Skills**

### **Programming**

C++ C# JavaScript HTML - CSS ReactJS - JSX React Three Fiber Framer Motion

### **Software**

Unreal Engine Unity Visual Studio 3DSMax Blender

#### Services

GitHub GitHub Pages Netlify Assembla Trello

### Personal

Punctual Responsible Honest Challenge-Accepting

## **Professional Summary**

**Game and Front-End Developer** with **3 years** of combined experience excelling in Al Programming and Gameplay Elements such as Al and Player Interfacing, Player Movement, Networking, Level Elements and more.

Worked on multiple deadline-driven projects with big and small groups.

Shifting the same knowledge onto Front-End applications made with React, and several other NodeJS packages such as Redux, Framer Motion, ThreeJs etc.

Rewarded by being listed in **Dean's Honor List every semester**.

References available upon request.

### **Education**

### **Algonquin College**

Game Development (3 Years Advanced Diploma) Specializing in Programming Cumulative GPA: 3.85 / 4.0 September 2019 - April 2022

### Udemy

Modern React with Redux (3 Months) Summer of 2021 - Certificate

3D Programming with JavaScript and the Three.js 3D Library (1 Month) Summer of 2021 - Certificate

## **Experience**

### **Capstone Project**

Al and Gameplay Programmer for Particle Interactive (8 Months) Implemented Al with Behaviour Trees C++, Grapple Hook, etc. Working on Project Steelwalker over the course of a school year. September 2021 – Current

### **Dreamlight**

Gameplay Programmer for Tapscone Studios (4 Months)
Implemented multiple gameplay features including AI, Event Triggers and
Gameplay Elements such as Kill Boxes, Moving Platforms, Checkpoints, etc.
All documented and available upon request.
January 2021 – April 2021

#### Particle Interactive Company Website - Link

Hosted on Netlify, made using ReactJS and maintained using GitHub. November 2021